In this clip we are cleaning the dirty wax off of the surfboard so that we can start with a clean surface.
We are going to use a base coat of wax and then a top coat of wax in order to create grip so we don't slip: that would be a rookie mistake.
We will even add texture using the teeth side of the wax comb.
I'm fortunate to have a hot sunny afternoon.
I am taking the old dirty wax off with the straight edge of the wax comb.
Remember to dispose of properly.
Now that I've got my board nice and clean, I am going to start applying a base coat of wax so the top coat takes.
Where you wax the board is going to be influenced by where your feet are going to go.
On a shortboard, my feet are going to go around here, front feet around here, the middle of the board.
If I was riding a longboard and I was trying to nose ride, I would get up to the tip, I would wax up there as well.
Once we have the base coat applied, which is a harder wax, we could put on the top coat, which is a softer wax and a grippier wax.
Now that I have got the wax applied and if I want even more texture and more grip, I'll use the teeth of the wax comb in a crossing pattern to give me a nice grid.
If you don't have fresh wax, I recommend a fresh coat before you start to go surfing.
It that's not handy and all you have is wax comb, this will get your through it.
And if you don't have a wax comb, a little beach sand will add texture and get you through.